Catherine Lynk

http://catherinelynk.com catherine.lynk@gmail.com 847-902-1751

PROFILE

Digital designer with a focus on user experience and a deep understanding of the system development lifecycle. As a client delivery team member, I have conducted research, synthesized data to drive business decisions, documented diagrams and wireframes and collaborated effectively across functional teams.

EXPERIENCE

DESIGNATION Labs

March 2015 - Present

UX / UI Design Apprentice

Anjoui - User Experience Research & Interaction Design

- Provided user experience and interaction design direction to a peer-to-peer mobile application start-up that connects home cooks with local diners
- Evaluated heuristics of the initial design, expanded wireframes through 3 rounds of usability testing and created a mid-fidelity, functional prototype
- Enabled stakeholders to interact with their concept for the first time and accelerated the timeframe from design to launch

Package Zen - User Experience Research & Content Strategy

- Addressed user experience challenges on an enterprise mobile solution that simplifies package management in offices, mailrooms and sports arenas
- Created a process map, task model and 20+ discrete wireframes based on qualitative interviews and onsite observation
- Clarified the mental model of the primary user base, allowing new features to be rolled out without disturbing the users' core workflow

ALLSTATE INSURANCE July 2014 - February 2015

Senior Consultant

- Evaluated emerging technologies, identified opportunities for enterprise innovation and presented recommendations to technology leadership
- Established internal processes based on the design thinking approach for continued use by the technology strategy team

DELOITTE CONSULTING August 2011 - July 2014

Consultant

Technology Transformation

- Led business requirement sessions with subject matter experts and documented user flows for the development of a global software product
- Facilitated co-creation exercises and worked with the development team to improve usability by reducing the number of clicks to complete key tasks

Project Management

- Designed a global governance model to plan and implement an insurance claims solution across 3 international regions and 7 lines of business
 Developed a macro for analyzing and visualizing financial metrics to reduce
- costs and drive growth for the Deloitte Solutions Center

EDUCATION

University of Illinois 2007 - 2011 at Urbana-Champaign College of Business

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems & Information Technology

Bachelor of Science in Marketing

Bocconi University

Milan, Italy University of Illinois Study Abroad

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Digital Design

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Axure InVision Proto.io Sketch

Front-End Development

HTML5 / CSS3 JavaScript

System Transformation

Guidewire Systems HP Quality Center MS Office Suite MS SharePoint Pega Systems

HONORS

Allstate Technology & Operations Applause Awards

Deloitte Insurance Technology Spotlight Award

Deloitte Consulting Candidate Lead for University of Illinois Recruiting